Alejandro Salazar Molina

↑ AlejoSalazarM | in AlejoSalazarM | ■ alejosalazar.mol@gmail.com | 1 +57 300 6498380

Professional Background

Professional in Social Communication and Journalism with experience in creating internal and external communication strategies, developing and writing content for media positioning, creating internal use materials, knowledge in data analytics, as well as in Python and R languages, responsible for monitoring KPIs and creating monthly and annual reports. With high capacity for assisting in different projects and public relations. Interest in social issues, technology, data insights, communication for social change, peacebuilding, international cooperation, Sustainable Development Goals, marketing, brand creation and economy.

Work Experience

GJ Comunicaciones

October 2021 - present

Senior Account Executive

Responsible for fulfilling and following up on the different requirements of clients in the agency's brand area in order to support their internal and external communication plans, designing proposals for their launches and openings, communicating milestones of each brand through tools such as social media, media outlets, events, and influencer marketing, responsible for tracking KPIs and creating reports.

Edelman March 2021 - August 2021

Account Executive

At Edelman, I supported the creation of internal and external communication strategies that drove the positioning of different clients and their business objectives. Among my duties, I managed communication actions for the launch of new stores and products supported by influencer marketing. Additionally, I contacted media outlets to generate free press and strengthen the relationship between brand spokespeople and opinion leaders in the country. I also took care of creating monthly and annual reports on the management of each account. In crisis situations, I generated ideas and insights with the support of my colleagues to protect clients' reputation and provide reactive messaging when necessary. Clients served: Nubank, Starbucks, Domino's, Spotify, SES, and Espacolaser.

McCann Ericksonn

January 2019 - March 2021

Junior Associate

Implementation and execution of internal and external communication plans for different clients, development of press content for brands with the aim of promoting their projects in media outlets, management of public relations, creation of monthly reports and reports, support for the communications office of each client, brand positioning and relationship building with target audiences. Clients served: Primax Colombia S.A. (formerly ExxonMobil), Faculty of Management of Universidad de los Andes, The MBA Tour, Hero Motos, IBM, Aon, Ericsson, and oBoticário.

Spain Embassy in Colombia

February 2018 - August 2018

Intern

Assisting the communications department of the Agency, managing social media and the website, creating different designs and materials required for the visibility of AECID's projects, developing press releases, media monitoring, social media reports, and following the visibility protocol for activities carried out by third parties supported by Spanish Cooperation.

Manos Visibles ONG

April 2017 - December 2017

Community manager

Supporting the development of communication strategies for the dissemination and promotion of the various programs and projects carried out by the Corporation, executing proposed communication campaigns, and creating content and products.

EDUCATION

2022 - present Master degree in Data Analytics **Universidad Central** 2013 - 2019 Degree in Social Communication and Journalism **Universidad Central**

SKILLS

- English B2
- Relationship building with media and journalists
- Knowledge of programming languages such as Python and R.
- Influencer marketing
- Report writing and creation
- Development of social media content such as grids
- Tracking KPI's and business objectives
- Spokesperson training, key message creation, communication plans, branded and unbranded strategies.
- Media monitoring

Personal references

Available upon request.

Last update: March 5 2023